Finding Aid for the Ralph Greenson Papers LSC.1497
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph Greenson papers
1934-1979
UCLA Library Special Collections
Greenson, Ralph R. (Ralph Romeo)
LSC.1497
19 Linear Feet (38 boxes and 3 oversize boxes)
The Ralph Greenson papers includes correspondence, writings (including lectures and published papers), tape recordings, and materials relating to teaching. In 1953, Greenson started teaching at UCLA. He is best known for writing The technique and practice of psychoanalysis. He also wrote Explorations in psychoanalysis, as well as 53 scientific papers.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Some materials restricted until 2039.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Ralph Greenson, 1986.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914706693606533
Biography
Ralph Romeo Greenson (actually Romeo Samuel Greenschpoon) was born on September 20, 1911 in Brooklyn, New York. After high school in New York he attended Columbia University, from where he graduated in 1930. He then completed his MD at The University of Bern in 1934 before doing further postgraduate work at Cedars of Lebanon Hospital in Los Angeles, Allgemeines Krankenhaus in Vienna, Austria, the Topeka Psychoanalytic Institute, and the San Francisco Psychoanalytic Institute. He started a private practice in psychiatry and psychoanalysis in Los Angeles in 1934, which he continued in Beverly Hills after four years in the U.S. Army Air force Medical Corps from 1942 to 1946. In 1953 he started teaching at UCLA. He is best known for writing The technique and practice of psychoanalysis. He also wrote Explorations in psychoanalysis, as well as 53 scientific papers. He was a founding member of the Los Angeles Psychoanalytic Society and a life member of the American Psychoanalytic Association. Greenson died November 24, 1979.
Scope and Content
The collection includes correspondence, writings (including lectures and published papers), tape recordings, and materials relating to teaching.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
U.S. Army service
Articles (translations)
Biographical material
Captain Newman, M.D.
Colleagues
Correspondence
Discussions of papers by
Dream seminars
Early lecture-seminars
Ernst Simmel
Greenson seminars
Lectures and broadcast by Ralph Greenson
Lectures and patient notes
Medical aspects of human sexuality
Miscellaneous papers
Notes and articles
Otto Fenichel
Panels
Patient sessions
Private practice
Professional organizations
Psychoanalytic associations and institutes
Psychoanalytic process
Public lectures
Publication of books
Published articles
Published papers
Short stories
Technique and Practice of Psychoanalysis Volume II
Technique
Unpublished papers
West Los Angeles Mental Health Center
Wilhelm Stekel.
Psychoanalysis.; Greenson, Ralph R. (Ralph Romeo)
- Army - WWII
  - Seminar: Yuma, AZ - Air Corps Gunnery School - Army lectures, no date (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Fort Logan, Denver, CO - convalescent hospital - Army lectures, no date (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Practical approach to the War neuroses - paper, no date (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sodium pentathol interviews - typed case histories & progress reports, no date (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sodium pentathol interviews (folder 1 of 2), 1944 - 1945 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Scope and Contents note
    Progress reports - holograph notes.
  - Sodium pentathol interviews (folder 2 of 2), 1944 - 1945 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Army transfer records, 1944 - 1946 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 201 file, Scott Field - injury report - commendation medal, 1944 - 1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Letters from soldiers, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Magazines - 4 items, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - RRG cash book, 1939 - 1942 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - War neuroses in North Africa - by Roy R. Grinker & John P. Spiegel, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Psychiatric experiences of the Eighth Air Force by Donald W. Hastings, David G. Wright, Bernard C. Glueck, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Army & Air Force instructional & propaganda publications - 7 items, no date (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Articles - translations
  - L'empathie et ses phases diverses - Revue Francaise de Psychanalyse, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Homosexualite et identite sexuelle - Revue Francaise de Psychanalyse, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Das Arbeitsbuendnis unde die Uebertragungsneurose - Psyche: Eine Zeitschrift fuer Psychologische unde Medizinische Menschenkunde, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Il rapporto non transferenziale nella situazione analitica - Estratto dall Rivista di Psycoanalisi, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Die Uebertragungsfreie Beziehung in der Psychoanalytischen Situation - Psyche ..., 1971 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Au-dela du transfert et de l'interpretation - Le Coq Heron, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Alem da Transferencia e da Interpretacao - Revista brasiliera de Psicanalise, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Transferencia: Freud o Klein - Psicologia Medica, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Zum Problem der Empathie - Psyche: Eine Zeitschrift ..., no date (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Biographical material
  - CV's - RRG, 1960 - 1976 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Ralph Greenson scrapbook, 1942 - 1961 (Box 33)
- Captain Newman, M.D.
  - Press, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Rosten, Rudin & RRG, 1961 - 1964 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Colleagues
  - Party of the month - constitution, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Mortgage is not for burning by Joshua Sizzle [Hanna Fenichel & Margaret Monk], 1952 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    28 Dec.
- Correspondence
  - Telegram, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Melvin Levine, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - William Stekel, 1936 - 1938 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - William Stekel, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 39)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Box 19, folder 44 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 39)
    Box 20, folder 2 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 39)
    Box 20, folder 3 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 39)
    Box 20, folder 5 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39. With Lawrence S. Kubie.
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 39)
    Box 20, folder 6 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Hospital mail, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    9 April - 19 May.
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Letters for 50th birthday, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Patients - general, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Friends, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Colleagues, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Other, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Colleagues, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - PSA & institute, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - General, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Friends, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Friends, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Colleagues, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - General, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - PSA, UCLA, etc., 1965 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - General, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Colleagues, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Friends, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - PSA, UCLA, etc., 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Regarding scientific papers, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Mental health, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - PSA & institutes, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Patients, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Colleagues & friends, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Foundation for Research in Preventive Psychiatry, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Psychiatric, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - PSA, institute, society & mental health, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Psychiatric, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Scientific papers, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Patients, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Colleagues & friends, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Colleagues & friends, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - PSA & psychiatric, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Public, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Patients, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - PSA & psychiatric, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Trip & miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Re: scientific papers, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Public mental health, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Patients, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Colleagues & friends, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Patients, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Colleagues, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Scientific papers, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Public mental health, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - PSA & psychiatric, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Patients, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous & friends, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Colleagues, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Scientific papers, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Psychiatric & university, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Public mental health, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Society & institute, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Patients, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous & friends, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Psychiatric, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Psychoanalytic Institute & publish, 1973 (Box 39)
    Box 25, folder 1 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
  - Colleagues, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Re: scientific papers, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Public mental health & Foundation for Research in Psychoanalysis (FRIP), 1973 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Scientific papers, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous & friends, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Colleagues, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Mental health, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Psychiatric, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Patients, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Society & institutes, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Technique & practice, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Scientific papers, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Technique & practice, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Patients, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Psychiatric, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Friends & miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Mental health, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Institute & society, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Colleagues, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Patients, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Mental health, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Technique & practice, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Institute & society, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Psychiatric, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - FRIP - end, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Scientific papers, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous & friends, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Colleagues, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Scientific papers, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Patients, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Psychiatric, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Mental health, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Friends & miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Colleagues, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Institute & PSA, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Publishing & Exploration in Psychoanalysis, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Colleagues, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Mental health, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Patients, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Friends & miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Psychiatric, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Scientific papers, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Institute & colleagues, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Patients, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Scientific papers, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Mental health, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Friends, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Psychiatric, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Colleagues, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Institute, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Correspondence - Anna Freud
  - Correspondence, 1947 - 1949 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1950 - 1952 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1954 - 1955 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1980 - 1982 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Hanna Fenichel to Anna Freud & Janus Strachey, no date (Box 28, Folder 24)
- Discussion of papers by
  - Kubie, Lawrence: Unresolved problems concerning resolution of transference, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Limentani, A. Re-evaluation of acting out in relation to working through, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    IJP, vol. 47.
  - Ritvo, S. Correlation of childhood & adult neuroses, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    IJP, vol. 47. 2 copies.
  - Niederland, W.G. Contribution to the psychology on gambling, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    PSA Forum, vol. 2.
  - Pumpian-Mindelin, E. Panel discussion report on DEFENSE ORGANISATION OF THE EGO & PSYCHOANALYTIC TECHNIQUE, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    JAMPA, vol. 15. R. Waelder, chairman.
  - Mahler, M. [No title], 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    "Probably lecture to LA - PSA"
  - Arlow & Brenner. The psychopathology of the psychoses, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    IJP, vol. 50.
  - Stoller, R. The impact of new advances in sex research on psychoanalytic theory, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Pao, Ping-Nie. On hypomania, no date (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ticho, E. The effect of the psychoanalyst's personality on the treatment, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Kernberg, O. A critique of "Summary and conclusions", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    IJP, vol. 2, no. 3, p. 3-73.
  - Schlesinger, H. In defense of denial, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lichtenberg & Slap. General functioning of the analyst in the psychoanalytic situation, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    With copy of RRG's paper.
  - Brenner, C. Analysis of dreams & of neurotic symptoms, no date (1975?) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Dream seminars [cassettes]
  - Dream seminars [1 of 8], 1974 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Post aphasia. 15 October.
  - Dream seminars [2 of 8], 1974 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    #1 & 2. 29 October.
  - Dream seminars [3 of 8], 1974 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    #3 & 4. 29 October.
  - Dream seminars [4 of 8], 1974 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    12 November.
  - Dream seminars [5 of 8] - new dreams, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    3 December.
  - Dream seminars [6 of 8], 1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    17 December.
  - Dream seminars [7 of 8] - narcissism, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    7 January.
  - Dream seminars [8 of 8], 1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    21 January.
- Early lecture-seminars
  - Introduction to psychoanalytic child psychology - (1 of 3), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Typed outline notes. (23 October)
  - Introduction to psychoanalytic child psychology (2 of 3), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Typed outline notes. (30 October)
  - Introduction to psychoanalytic child psychology (3 of 3), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Typed outline notes. (6 November)
  - Paper: object relationships of latency, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Latency.
  - Typed outline notes: latency I thru IX, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Notes - latency, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Lecture series: Psychoanalysis of childhood - oral phase, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Lecture series: Psychoanalysis of childhood - anal phase - notes, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Lecture series: Psychoanalysis of childhood - puberty & adolescence - typed notes & holograph outlines (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Notes summarizing psychoanalysis of childhood, 1950? (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Theory of instincts, 1950? (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Acting out - Early chapters for Technique Chpts VII and VIII, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Counter-transference - Early chapters for Technique Chapts VII and VIII, no date (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Notes on theory & technique of dream interpretation, 1964, 1965, 1972, no date (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Ernst Simmel
  - Banquet speech at 10-year celebration of Psychoanalytic Study Group [by Ernst Simmel], 1945 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    5 October. 13 pages.
- Grant
  - Correspondence with Friends Medical Science Research Center, Inc. (Baltimore, MD), 1971 - 1978 (Box 39)
    Box 19, folder 12 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
- Greenson seminars
  - Fundamentals of psychoanalytic technique, 1959 - 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Course outlines and reading list.
  - Preliminary interviews I, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Opening phase.
  - Preliminary interviews II, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary interviews III, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Conclusion.
  - Analyzability, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Practical issues, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dynamics of psychoanalytic treatment, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Resistance I, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Resistance II, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Transference I, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Transference II, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Transference III, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Transference IV, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Empathy I, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Empathy II, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Empathy III, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dosage, timing and tact I, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Dosage, timing and tact II, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dosage, timing and tact III, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Dosage, timing and tact IV, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dosage, timing and tact V, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Dosage, timing and tact VI, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Dosage, timing and tact VII, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Rules for interpretation, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Interpretation from the structural point of view, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Acting out I, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Acting out II, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Acting out III, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Countertransference I, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Countertransference II, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Countertransference III, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Countertransference IV, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Working through I, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Working through II, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Termination I, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Termination II, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Termination III, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Dream seminar, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Treatment sequences & dream segments.
  - Suitability & analyzability, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Typed paper & transcript.
  - Suitability revisited, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Incomplete transcript.
  - Review of Strachey's 1934 paper, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Notes.
  - Transition to psychoanalysis, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Lectures & broadcasts by RRG [cassettes]
  - Notes: discussions with Leites re: Fees, no date (Box Unknown container 208 for instance of Notes: discussions with Leites re: Fees, Folder unknown container)
  - On violence lecture, no date (Box Unknown container 209 for instance of On violence lecture, Folder unknown container)
    1 / 3 only.
  - Tape #6, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    1 reel. UCLA. 18 June.
  - Psychological testing, pt. 2 & Dreams, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - First interview & psychological testing, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    UCLA?
  - Transference interpretation only? - seminar & Leites paper, no date (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Transference seminar, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    1 of 2.
  - Transference seminar, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    2 of 2.
  - Strachey paper seminar, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Selectivity? or errors, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    1 of 3
  - Selectivity? or errors, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    2 of 3
  - Selectivity? or errors, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    3 of 3
  - Selectivity for psychoanalytic to candidates, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Analyzability seminar - Foster presents, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Errors in psychotherapy, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    San Francisco. 1 of 2.
  - Errors in psychotherapy, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    San Francisco. 2 of 2.
  - Sex without passion, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Laughter & tears, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Laughter & tears, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Violence, environmental pollution, etc., no date (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Melanie Klein, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Workshop report.
  - Interracial transference & countertransference, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    UCLA? 1 of 3.
  - Interracial transference & countertransference, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    UCLA? 2 of 3.
  - Interracial transference & countertransference, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    UCLA? 3 of 3.
  - Changing pattern in love & sex, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Mistakes & beginnings, no date (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Audio health lectures.
  - Sleep, dreams & death, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    1 and 2 of 3.
  - Sleep, dreams & death, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    3 of 3.
  - Sleep, dreams & death, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Psychotherapy, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Psychotherapy, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Transference: Freud or Klein, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Beyond sexual satisfaction, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Letters dictation, no date (Box 15)
  - Hampstead Centre film, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Soundtrack.
  - Notes: consultation, no date (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Perils of loving, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions.
  - Notes to secretary, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Letters re: adolescence and suicide.
  - Interview, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    By Susan Steinman.
  - APA meeting, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    May.
  - APSA meeting & workshop - tape 1 [of 2], 1976 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - APSA meeting & workshop - tape 2 [of 2], 1976 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Selection - Klein presents, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Transference: Freud or Klein, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    20 September.
  - Communicative material, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Seminar re: Shane paper. 4 December.
  - Communicative material, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Seminar re: Shane paper. 29 January.
  - Psychological testing, no date (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Dictation for vol III introduction.
- Lectures & broadcasts by RRG [large reels]
  - Lecture 1 - oral phase, Lecture 2 - anal sadistic phase (incomplete), 1950 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    1 reel.
  - Lecture 3 - anal phase, Lecture 4 - Phallic phase (cont'd next reel), 1950 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Lecture IV, cont. - phallic phase, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - How the psychoanalyst looks at the family physician, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Reiss - Davis Child Study Center. 1 reel.
  - Conflict between psychoanalysis and religion (Tape 1 of 2), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Reiss Davis Child Study Center. 1 reel.
  - Conflict between psychoanalysis and religion (Tape 2 of 2), 1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)